environment-agency.gov.uk 2007-12-11

# Environment Agency - Privacy policy

Statement of intent

In order to access the services we provide and to provide us with feedback, you will be asked to submit personal information about yourself (e.g. name, address, and telephone number). The services provided include licence application, environmental information, provision of feedback and consultations.

By entering your details the Environment Agency will be able to provide you with the services you select. Whenever you provide personal information, we undertake to treat that information in accordance with this policy.

Submitting personal information

When you supply personal information to the Environment Agency we have legal obligations towards you in the way we deal with that information. We have to process information within the framework of our statutory duties and powers and in addition we have to collect the information fairly. The individual notices on particular webpages, forms or specifically given to you let you know how we will use the information and whether we will pass the information on to anyone else.

Use and disclosure of personal information

We use personal information to deal with licence applications, to monitor compliance with the licence/permit/registration conditions, to process renewals, preventing and investigating breaches of environmental law, for maintaining the relevant public register(s), dealing with complaints, consultations and for providing environmental services and literature.

We may disclose personal data to our consultants, agents and representatives to do these things on our behalf. In addition we may disclose information to other public bodies and other organisations (e.g. Health and Safety Executive Local Authorities, Emergency Services, Defra) for consultation on environmental issues.

Personal information that we are required to put on our public registers may be licensed for re-use to third parties. Personal information that is not on a public register may be also be licensed to third parties, but this will only be where the Data Protection Act 1998 allows. If personal information not on the public register is licensed for marketing purposes this will only be for strictly limited types of marketing and where you have indicated you want this to happen. Personal information may also be shared with parties other than those mentioned above where we are required by law to disclose the information.

We will only hold personal data on our systems for a strictly limited period of time. For the most part the time period will be set as a matter of internal policy and will be the minimum necessary for our use.

Access to your personal information

You have the right to request a copy of the personal information the Environment Agency holds about you and to have any inaccuracies in that personal information corrected. Please address requests to the National Data Protection Manager or use the on-line enquiry form.  

Direct marketing

From time to time we may wish to provide you with details of other services or literature about environmental matters available from the Environment Agency which may be of interest to you. We may also offer you the opportunity to participate in the consultation process for new methods, strategies, works or schemes proposed by the Environment Agency.

Users under 18

If you are under 18, please make sure that you obtain your parent/guardian's permission beforehand whenever you provide personal information to the Environment Agency on its website or by other means.

Security of personal information

We share the general concern over the safety and security of personal information on the Internet and have implemented procedures to promote the safety and security of information we collect online. We have implemented industry standard controls to try to ensure confidentiality; however, no data transmission over the Internet can be guaranteed to be 100% secure. We cannot therefore guarantee that personal information will never be disclosed in ways not otherwise described in this Privacy Policy.

Cookies 

Cookies are text files, which identify your computer to our server. Cookies in themselves do not identify the individual user, just the computer used. 

The Environment Agency uses two separate cookies to identify preferred language settings and text only preferences on the site. The World Environment Day section uses a cookie for personalisation and the Fun and Games section uses a cookie to retain user settings for the Changing Blooms game. 

We also use an external agent to analyse usage behaviour on our behalf. To enable this we use a ‘unique visitor cookie’ to obtain information about your use of our site, such as whether you have visited our site more than once and how you found us. 

This information allows us to more effectively tailor our site to make its use easier. Their privacy policy can be found at:[Nielsen//Netratings](http://www.netratings.com/privacy.jsp?section=leg_scs)

Through modification of browser preferences, you can elect to accept all cookies, receive notification when a cookie is set, or decline all cookies. You can find further information regarding the deletion of cookies can be found at: <http://www.aboutcookies.org/Default.aspx?page=2>[ ](http://www.aboutcookies.org/deletecookies.asp)
